Padam Banthia

+91-9660981507

padamb.jain24@gmail.com
http://linkedin.com/in/padambanthia



Professional Summary

Software Developer with experience in innovating and designing solutions for applications which creates high business impact by reducing time and errors. A polymath capable of multitasking with strong analytical and pragmatic mindset. Effective communicator to work with stakeholders and collaborate in team to drive product development success.

Work Experience

Software Engineer 1 | Dell Technologies Hyderabad, India (May, 2020 – Present) Analyst | Dell Technologies Hyderabad, India (July, 2019 – May, 2020)

Working with Tech SEO Team as automation developer to improve efficiency in day-to-day manual tasks

- Developed Sitemap Submission Tool to submit 50k+ sitemaps of dell.com on daily basis in Google search console to help web pages index in Google Search Engine once they are launched or modified.
- Implemented tool XML Feed for BazaarVoice which provides syndication of R&R and enabled section R&R on dell.com PD pages that gives customers a better insight of product they are buying which increased revenue per visit by 150%.
- Developed Redirection Suggester tool to provide Redirect Dell URL suggestion for old dell URLs that are live to remove duplication of content and improves ranking of new web pages in SERP by reducing time taken and errors by 95%.
- Designed tool to build Dashboard for generating audit reports of issues and fixes present in URL and Canonicals of dell.com using Python(Pandas) to reduce vulnerabilities present that helps webpages to index in Search Engines as top results and reduce identification and reporting time by 75%.

2) Winter Intern | Dell Technologies Hyderabad, India (January, 2019 – may, 2019)

Recruited by NPL Team to effectively manage the EOL requests coming from stakeholders

- Designed EOL Traffic Cop Bot using RPA to automatically assign the requests to developers based on their bandwidth and skillsets
- Devloped Support Image Tracker using Python which keeps record of all images present on different support pages of dell.com

3) Summer Intern | Dell International Services Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru, India (May 208-July 2018)

Worked on the Dell B2B Project to enable payment services in Dell Premier Portal.

o Integrated V3 Payment Services for Premier Cart and Checkout for Dell P+ team.

Education				
Year	Course	Name of Board/University	Percentage/CGPA	
2019	B.E(Hons.)	Chandigarh University	8.77	
2014	XII	C.B.S.E	90.6%	
2012	Y	CBSF	9.6	

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, SQL
- Domain Skills: Data Structures, Algorithm, Machine Learning(Beginner), Competitive Programmer
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- Technology Stack: MySQL, DB2, Github, Git, RPA(Automation Anywhere)

Accomplishments and Awards

- Ranked 11638 in IIT-JEE Advance 2015 Qualifier.
- Winner of AIR 1 in National Mathematics Olympiad at tech-Invent 2k17 at Chandigarh University
- Ranked AIR 11 in category 2(UG year 2) in NCAT 2016-17(National Creativity and Aptitude Test)
- Won Code Busters in a team of 2 at Tech-Fest 2017 of Govt. College S.A.S Nagar, Mohali
- Recommended as Mr. Confident in the farewell at Raman Munjal Vidya Mandir in standard 12
- Enlisted as Vice Marshal of Student Elective Body at Raman Munjal Vidya Mandir in standard 11.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Organized 5 events as Member of ITDP Innovation Committee in Dell Technologies, Hyderabad.
- Conducted 25+ events as Student Event Manager of Apex Institute of Technology(Computer Science engineering) at Chandigarh University for year 2017-18.
- Managed and Chapter Lead at CodeChef Campus Chapter Opt-Code to create programming culture in University by organizing 3 key events.
- Directed in successful organization of National Level Hackathon(CUHackOverFlow 1.0) at Tech-Invent 2k18 which included 180+ teams from different colleges in India

Professional Skills

- Assessed as Optimistic and Pragmatic person who analyzes problem statement by Design Thinking methodologies.
- Awarded 3 Winning Together Awards in Dell exhibiting Team Work and Co-ordination Skills.
- Won 2 Dell Awards for leading projects as Dev Lead with effective management and communication with Stakeholders

PERSONAL DOSSIER

Father's Name : Mr. Suparas Banthia Mother's Name : Mrs. Mamta Banthia Date of Birth : 24 March 1997

Address : #506, Block-J, Capital Greens, Bhiwadi, Rajasthan, India(301019)